You point out that there have been a number of countries, including South Africa, Bangladesh, Bolivia, Djibouti, et cetera, that have moved for the International Criminal Court to prosecute Israeli officials.
But all of the countries that have used the word genocide, called out Israel for enacting genocide in Gaza, have yet to invoke the Genocide Convention specifically.
And you have a theory as to why that might be the case.
Yeah, well, a lot of these countries have gone to the International Criminal Court.
The International Criminal Court has basically done the bidding of the U.S. and Israel in the many years of its existence.
It has proven to be a dead end, at least so far.
The current barrister made a little bit of noise that he might do the right thing, but he just went to Israel and he didn't go to Gaza.
So he's a British barrister.
And once again, it seems that the International Criminal Court isn't going to do its alleged job.
It goes after African dictators and it goes after Putin.
It doesn't go after Israel.
It doesn't go after NATO.
It doesn't go after the United States, no matter what they do.
There's another legal avenue, which is, as you say, invoking the Geneva Convention, invoking the Genocide Convention, which Israel is a party to.
It has signed that, unlike the International Criminal Court, unlike a lot of other international documents, it has signed the Genocide Convention.
Moreover, there's an article in the Genocide Convention that says that any party that's a signer to it can take another party if they even see the prospect that the name of the convention includes the word prevention.
That is, you invoke this even to prevent, not just simply to punish genocide, but to prevent it.
So if you see an ongoing genocide or potential genocide taking place, parties which are signatories to this treaty are rather obligated to invoke it.
So far, none have done so.
You can have South Africa.
You can have Bolivia.
You can have Colombia.
You can have Turkey.
You can have Iran.
You can have Venezuela.
All of these countries have either condemned Israel in the strongest terms or outright called it genocide.
But none of them have yet invoked this treaty.
It's especially important because the World Court, where this would be adjudicated, has proven to be somewhat responsive in the case of Palestine.
Years ago, they had a ruling on Israel's wall that was quite critical of Israel.
And they have also a ruling, a long-term ruling, which is also an advisory ruling, on the occupation as a whole that's due out next year.
This would be different.
Applying the Genocide Convention can enact an emergency procedure, which would have more teeth than their typical advisory opinions.
It would then be thrust again before the United Nations Security Council, and it would tremendously isolate the United States.
You would have a finding by the World Court that Israel is guilty of genocide.